1995年 一个名叫安迪的男孩在生日那天得到了一个巴斯光年玩具
In 1995, a boy named Andy got a Buzz Lightyear toy for his birthday.
这是他最喜欢的电影
It was from his favorite movie.
这就是那部电影
This is that movie.
距离地球420万光年的未知空间
UNCHARTED SPACE 4.2 MILLION LIGHT YEARS FROM EARTH
STAR司令部SC-01勘探船船员：1200人
STAR COMMAND SC-01 EXPLORATION VESSEL CREW: 1200
巴斯光年任务日志 恒星日期3901
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date 3901.
传感器检测到了潜在的生命形式
Sensors have detected potential life forms.
在一个未知的星球上
on an uncharted planet.
所以 我们绕道调查
So, we're making a detour to investigate.
太空巡游者将进行初步评估
Space Rangers will make initial evaluation,
然后评估是否值得唤醒科学团队
then assess whether it's worth waking the science crew
从他们的过度睡眠中
from their hyper-sleep.
当ERIC采集岩芯样本时
While the ERIC takes core samples
我将进一步探索这个奇怪星球的奇怪之处
I will explore further the oddities of this strange planet.
地形似乎有点不稳定
Terrain seems a bit unstable.
如果该区域透气 则尚未读取读数
No read-out yet if the area is breathable.
似乎任何地方都没有智慧生命的迹象
There seems to be no sign of intelligent life anywhere.
-你在跟谁说话-没有人
-Who are you talking to? -No one.
你又在叙述了
You were narrating again.
我没有 只是做任务日志
I was not. Just doing the mission log.
你知道没有人会听他们的
You do know no one ever listens to them.
我知道 叙事帮助我集中注意力
I know that, narrating helps me with focus.
-保持警惕-是 啊
-Stay sharp. -Yeah.
好吧 如果你不介意的话 霍桑指挥官
Well, if it bothers you, Commander Hawthorne.
我很高兴回来吃萝卜
I'm happy to wait back on the turnip.
请不要叫它萝卜
Please don't call it the turnip.
但这艘船看起来像根菜
But the ship looks like a root vegetable.
是的 你在设计审查时说得很清楚
Yes, you made that very clear at the design review.
你知道我叙述多久了？
How long have you known that I narrate?
永远因为你和我都是军校学员
Forever. Since you and I were cadets.
说到这里 你忘了带新人
Speaking of, you forgot to take the rookie with you.
啊 霍桑指挥官 你知道我对新手的感觉
Ah, Commander Hawthorne, you know how I feel about rookies.
这和我对自动驾驶仪的感觉是一样的
It's the same way I feel about autopilots.
“我能帮你什么忙吗？先生 有什么我能做的吗？”
"How may I assist you? Is there anything I can do, sir?"
他们没有帮助 只是把事情复杂化了
They don't help, they just over-complicate things.
我最好自己做这项工作
I'm better off just doing the job myself.
这就是为什么我要带新人来
Which is why I brought the rookie.
你好
Hello.
-不-巴兹 礼节要求我们带他一起去
-No. -Buzz, protocol requires we bring him along.
-他会有一双悲伤的眼睛-嗡嗡声
-He's gonna have sad eyes. -Buzz.
你知道我无法应付悲伤的眼神
You know I can't deal with sad eyes.
-看看这个新手 巴兹-不
-Look at the rookie, Buzz. -No.
-看看这辆车   看-不不
-Look at the roo...Look... -No...no.
-光年-不
-Lightyear. -No.
-看看他-没有看
-Look at him. -Not looking.
-看 看-不
-Look. Look. -No.
-看看这个新手-不 不
-Look at the rookie. -No. No.
好吧好吧你赢了
All right. All right. You win.
看 羽毛   Featheringhamstan
Look, Feather...Featheringhamstan...
这是费瑟林格姆斯坦 先生
It's Featheringhamstan, sir.
听着 菜鸟 首先 除非和你说话 否则你不会说话
Look, rookie, first, you will not speak unless spoken to.
-是的 先生-还在说话
-Yes, sir. -Still talking.
第二 尊重诉讼
Second, respect the suit.
这套衣服很有意义
This suit means something.
这不仅仅是保护你的身体 也是保护宇宙
It's not just protecting your body, it's protecting the universe.
这套西装是对世界的承诺
This suit is a promise to the world that you,
最重要的是 只有你一个人会做一件事
and you alone will do one thing above all.
芬兰人不惜代价完成任务
Finnish the mission no matter the cost.
你永远不会放弃 不管银河会给你什么样的选择--
You will never quit, whatever the galaxy may throw your way--
请把它关掉好吗！
Will you please turn that off!
这太容易了
It's just too easy.
你在嘲笑我 不是吗？
You're mocking me, aren't you?
是的 但以一种支持的方式
Yeah, but in a supportive way.
听着 我想说的是 指挥官 你和我有这份工作要做
Look, what I'm trying to say, Commander, is that you and I have this job down.
-先生-还在说话
-Sir. -Still talking.
我知道你在想什么 我知道你会在哪里
At any moment I know what you're thinking, I know where you're gonna be.
但是这个人 我不知道
But this guy, I don't know.
他去哪儿了？
Where'd he go?
你看到了吗？这正是我要说的
You see? This is exactly what I'm talking about.
他帮不上忙 他走失了
He's not helping. He's wandered off.
藤蔓！
Vines!
漏洞！
Bugs!
这艘船 它正在下沉
The ship. It's sinking.
大家 回到萝卜上来！
Everyone, back to the turnip!
哦 现在是萝卜了
Oh, so now it's the turnip.
进入隐身模式 这应该为我们赢得足够的时间
Engage Stealth Mode. That should buy us enough time.
我们不会成功的
We're not gonna make it.
快到了！
Almost there!
好的 B计划 准备好了吗？
Okay, plan B. Ready?
去
Go!
-爆炸-在这里 我可以重新路由它
-Blast! -Here, I can re-route it.
给我一分钟
Just give me a minute.
哪里是
Where is the...
帮助
Help!
菜鸟
rookie.
帮助我！
Help me!
巴斯光年任务日志 这颗行星显然不适合居住
Buzz Lightyear mission log. The planet is clearly uninhabitable.
事实上 他们完全怀有敌意
In fact, outright hostile.
有知觉的树叶抓住了羽化的学员
The sentient foliage have apprehended cadet Furth-Feathering...
费瑟林斯顿   羽毛
Featheringston...Feather...
他们找到了新人
They got the rookie,
我强烈建议他们不应该首先加入--
who I strongly suggested should not have joined in the first--
爆炸
Blast.
-巴斯-现在
-Buzz! -Now!
快走 流浪者！
Move it, ranger!
回到船上
Making our way back to the ship.
快点 巴兹！
Come on, Buzz!
匆忙
Hurry!
机舱一切都很好
All good at the engine room.
-我来掌舵-我会的--
-I'll take the helm. -And I will--
什么都不做 我有这个
Do nothing. I've got this.
我能为您做些什么？
How may I assist you?
自动驾驶仪
Autopilots.
-先生 有什么我能做的吗-不 不！
-Is there anything I can do, sir? -No and no!
这不是模拟
This is not a simulation.
指挥官 状态！
Commander, status!
燃油已接通
Fuel engaged.
所有系统运行
All systems go.
警告发射轨迹不稳定
Warning. Launch trajectory unsound.
来吧来吧
Come on. Come on.
碰撞即将发生
Collision imminent.
中止中止
Abort. Abort.
光年船长 你需要我的帮助吗？
Captain Lightyear, do you need my help?
-否定-你确定吗？
-Negative. -Are you sure?
我是巴斯光年 我总是很确定
I'm Buzz Lightyear. I'm always sure.
s、 苏的ub bT
s.ub by su.b .T
很糟糕 巴兹
It's bad, Buzz.
超高速水晶被彻底摧毁
The hyper-speed crystal was totally destroyed.
长话短说：我们被孤立了
Long story short: we're marooned.
我不知道
I don't know.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我在追求自己的职业化
I'm court-martialing myself.
不 你不是
No. You're not.
霍桑指挥官 我特此解除我自己的所有太空护林员职责
Commander Hawthorne, I hereby relieve myself of all Space Ranger duties.
这是我的错 这些人应该得到更好的待遇
This was my fault. And these people deserve better.
你可以把我关进禁闭室
You can throw me in the brig.
完成任务 巴兹
Finish the mission, Buzz.
我们就是这么做的
That's what we do.
直到所有人都回家 我们才结束
We're not done until everyone gets home.
但我们没有燃料晶体
But we have no fuel crystal.
所以我们在这个星球上开采资源 创造一种新的水晶
So we mine resources on this planet, create a new crystal.
晶体融合是高度不稳定的
Crystalic fusion is highly unstable.
然后我们测试它
Then we test it.
不 太危险了
No. It's too dangerous.
制造超高速晶体
Manufacturing a crystal capable of hyper-speed
就像试图用太阳套索一样
is like trying to lasso with the sun.
然后需要有人把太阳系在船上
And then someone would need to attach that sun to a ship,
然后飞船需要有人驾驶它而不会让自己被遗忘
and then the ship needs someone to fly it without blowing themselves into oblivion.
那些头脑正常的人会
Who in their right mind would...
巴斯光年任务日志 恒星日期3902
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date 3902.
在被放逐整整一年之后
After a full year of being marooned,
我们的专业团队
our specialized crew
已经将这个星球的巨大资源投入了难以置信的使用
have put this planet's vast resources to incredible use.
最后 我们的第一次超高速试飞成功了
Finally, our first hyper-speed test flight is a go.
准备好了吗 光年船长？
Ready, Captain Lightyear?
准备好了 霍桑指挥官
Ready as I'll ever be, Commander Hawthorne.
无限大
To infinity.
甚至更远
And beyond.
-巴斯-我们在周围发现了一个缺口
-Buzz! -We got a breach in the perimeter.
拜托 我只是
Come on, I just...
光年船长！
Captain Lightyear!
飞行员迪亚兹
Airman Diaz.
伙计 今天的葡萄藤有点辣 是吗？
Boy, the vines are a little feisty today, huh?
我们准备好发射了吗？
Are we ready to launch?
如果你准备好了 我们都准备好了 先生
We're all ready if you are, sir.
一年的工作 四分钟的飞行 这不是什么吗？
A year of work for a four minute flight. Isn't that something?
当然可以
Sure is.
好吧 让我们看看这种新的超高速燃油是否稳定
Well, let's go find out if this new hyper-speed fuel is stable.
所以我可以让我们离开这块岩石
So I can get us off this rock.
我差点忘了 先生 这是您的静脉注射号码
I almost forgot. Here's your I.V.A.N, sir.
满载
Fully loaded.
自动驾驶仪
Autopilots.
当然 这里是XL-01
And here, of course, is the XL-01.
非常甜蜜的旅程
Pretty sweet ride.
现在让我们给你拿燃料晶体
Now let's get you that fuel crystal.
早上好 光年船长
Good morning, Captain Lightyear.
这是你特制的混合燃料
Here is your specially formulated fuel mixture.
这就是要达到超高速的燃料？
So, this is the fuel that's gonna reach hyper-speed?
它有87.6%的可能性
It has an 87.6 percent chance.
我愿意冒这个险
I'll take those odds.
祝你好运 船长
Good luck, Captain.
我们都指望你
We're all counting on you...
飞行员
Airman.
XL-01呼叫任务控制 你收到了吗？
XL-01 to Mission Control. Do you copy?
复制 XL-01
Copy, XL-01.
我给你四分钟离开地球
I'm gonna grant you four minutes to be off planet,
但是你马上就回来了
but then you come right back to us.
这是命令
That's an order.
收到
Roger that.
超高速 我来了
Hyper Speed, here I come.
T减10
T minus 10...
...九
...nine...
...八 七
...eight, seven...
...六
...six...
...五 四
...five, four...
...三 二
...three, two...
...一发射
...one. Launch.
一、 V.A.N.请拿出飞行计划
I.V.A.N., pull up the flight plan, please.
你好我是你的内在--
Hello. I am your internal--
自动驾驶仪
Autopilots.
您好 我是您的内部声控导航器 请叫我I.V.A.N
Hello, I am your internal voice-activated navigator, call me I.V.A.N.
请准备好飞行计划 I.V.A.N
Ready the flight plan, please, I.V.A.N.
当然
Certainly.
你的任务是加速穿越深太空
Your mission is to accelerate through deep space,
阿尔法·特卡尼周围的弹弓
slingshot around Alpha T'Kani,
然后通过减速环回到这里到T'kani素数
then through the deceleration rings back here to T'kani Prime.
目标飞行时间：4分28秒
Target flight time: 4 minutes, 28 seconds.
XL-01 您已准备好进行超级发布
XL-01, you are clear for hyper-launch.
复制 控制 正在启动hyper launch
Copy, control. Initiating hyper-launch.
接近50%的超高速
Approaching 50 percent hyper speed.
燃油稳定
Fuel stable.
将速度提高到0.6c
Increasing speed to 0.6c.
60%超高速
Sixty percent hyper-speed.
将速度提高到0.7c
Increasing speed to 0.7c.
70%超高速
Seventy percent hyper-speed.
燃油稳定
Fuel stable.
接近0.8摄氏度
Approaching 0.8c.
推动超高速
Pushing to hyper-speed.
发动机1故障
Failure in Engine 1.
燃料电池不稳定
Fuel cell unstable.
一、 V.A.N. 状态
I.V.A.N., status.
轨迹误差 加上四度
Trajectory error, plus four degrees.
不正确的航向将导致吊环丢失
Failure to course-correct will result in missing the rings.
我们将飞向太空深处
We'll fly off into deep space
导致一定的死亡
resulting in certain death.
是的 谢谢
Yes, thank you.
弹射是你唯一的选择
Ejection is your only option.
不 不 我能行
No, no. I can do it.
警告你有26秒的时间修正航向
Warning. You have 26 seconds to course-correct.
你现在有25秒的时间修正航向
You now have 25 seconds to course-correct.
-你现在有了——请停止计数
-You now have-- -Stop counting, please.
我很抱歉 我的安全协议禁止我终止倒计时
I'm sorry. My safety protocols prohibit me from terminating countdown.
自动驾驶仪
Autopilots.
任务即将失败 请记下你最后的话
Mission failure imminent. Please record your last words.
今天不行 I.V.A.N
Not today, I.V.A.N.
如果您对此录音满意 请讲话或选择1
If you are satisfied with this recording, speak or select 1.
一、 V.A.N.把引擎推到底 最大功率
I.V.A.N., push the engines all the way. Maximum power.
这种行动是不可取的 燃料电池爆炸--
That action is inadvisable. Fuel cell detonation--
这正是我所指望的
Is exactly what I'm counting on.
情况危急
Situation critical.
燃料电池接近峰值容量
Fuel cell approaching peak capacity.
打开燃油门 I.V.A.N
Open up the Fuel Door, I.V.A.N.
我很抱歉 我不太明白
I'm sorry. I didn't quite catch that.
-请重申你的命令-打开燃油门！
-Please restate your command. -Open fuel door!
五分钟后爆炸
Detonation in five...
...四
...four...
...三
...three...
...二
...two...
-...一个-现在
-...one. -Now!
课程已纠正
Course corrected.
你没有达到超高速
You failed to reach hyper-speed.
我不想听 I.V.A.N
I didn't need to hear that, I.V.A.N.
你没听到吗？
You didn't hear that?
哦 对不起 我重复一遍
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll repeat.
-不 我听说——我的意思是——你没能达到超高速
-No, I've heard-- I meant-- -You failed to reach hyper-speed.
-谢谢你 I.V.A.N.-你没能联系到--
-Thank you, I.V.A.N. -You failed to reach--
指挥官 你还好吗？
Commander, are you okay?
迪亚兹 你留胡子了
Diaz, you grew a beard.
你是怎么留胡子的？
How did you grow a beard?
哦 对了
Oh, right.
首先 欢迎回来
First of, welcome back.
其次
Secondly...
等待
Wait.
等等 这是什么？
Wait, what is this?
我走了多久？
How long was I gone?
四年零两个月零三天
Four years, two months and three days.
什么
What?
我以为我们失去了你 巴兹
I thought we've lost you, Buzz.
艾丽莎 发生什么事了？
Alisha, what happened?
-时间膨胀-什么
-Time dilation. -What?
时间膨胀很简单
Time dilation is quite simple.
当你接近超高速时 你的时间相对于我们的时间变慢了
As you approached hyper-speed, your time slowed relative to our own.
所以 在你的任务中 你只衰老了几分钟
So, during your mission you aged only minutes,
而我们其他人已经老了
while the rest of us have aged years.
简而言之：你飞得越快--
Simply put: The faster you fly--
我飞得越快 我旅行的距离就越远
The faster I fly the further into the future I travel.
我明白了
I get it.
那么 我们现在要做什么？
So, what are we gonna do now?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我认为我们应该推迟更多的试飞
But I think we should hold off on any more test flights
直到我们找到别的办法
until we've figured out something else.
指挥官 我们说完成任务
Commander, we said finish the mission.
太空漫游者就是这样做的
That's what Space Rangers do.
Buzz 代价是什么？
At what cost, Buzz?
你愿意再失去四年吗？
Are you willing to lose another four years?
所以每个人都被困在这里
So, everyone is just stuck here
因为我
because of me.
嘿 你还好吗？
Hey, you all right?
是 啊是 啊我很好
Yeah. Yeah. I'm fine.
等等 那是什么？
Wait, what's that?
哦 我订婚了
Oh, I got engaged.
哦 哇 太好了 她叫什么名字？
Oh, wow. That's great. What's her name?
意大利美妆口红品牌她是科学团队的一员
Kiko. She's one of the science crew.
有趣的是 如果我们没有被困 这一切都不会重要
It's funny, it never would've mattered if we hadn't been stranded.
你和刚认识的人订婚了？
You got engaged to someone you just met?
巴斯 我三年前见过她
Buzz, I met her three years ago.
哦 对了 正当
Oh, right. Right.
好吧 祝贺你 我很想见她
Well, Congratulations. I'd love to meet her.
嗯 还有很多时间 休息一下
Well, there's plenty of time for that. Get some rest.
这是命令
That's an order.
不客气！阿丽莎
YOU'RE WELCOME! ALISHA
你好 巴兹！
Hello, Buzz!
我是Sox 你的个人伴侣机器人
I am Sox. Your personal companion robot.
我的什么？
My what?
我是由星际司令部发布的
I was issued by star command
来缓解你离开后的情绪转变
to ease your emotional transition after your time away.
哦 你真体贴 机器猫
Oh, that's very considerate of you, robot feline.
但不用了 谢谢
But no thank you.
恐怕这是礼节
I'm afraid it's protocol.
传感器显示你错过了四个生日
Sensors indicate you've missed four birthdays.
你想要一套糖霜点心来庆祝吗？
Would you like a frosted snack kit to celebrate?
消极的那会损害我的营养团
Negative. That would compromise my nutritional regiment.
我们可以谈谈你的感受 我是一个优秀的倾听者
We can talk about your feelings. I am an excellent listener.
不 不 看 我经历了很长时间   白天
No, no. Look, I've had a very long... day?
事情没有按计划进行
It did not go as planned.
任务失败了？
The mission was unsuccessful?
肯定的
Affirmative.
哦 不 听到这个消息我很难过
Oh, no. I am so sorry to hear that.
谢谢你 Sox
Thank you, Sox.
不客气 巴兹
You're welcome, Buzz.
我们玩个游戏好吗？
Shall we play a game?
-不用了 谢谢-你确定吗？
-No, thank you. -Are you sure?
我可以根据你的具体个性特征 专门为你制作一款游戏
I can create a game specifically for you, based on your exact personality profile.
嘿 听着 Sox 伙计 我很累
Hey, listen, Sox, buddy, I'm pretty tired.
所以 我要继续努力
So, I'm gonna go ahead and hit the rack.
当然
Of course.
如果你喜欢 我可以提供睡眠声音
I can provide sleep sounds if you like.
我有几个选择
I have several options.
夏夜 海洋​​天堂 鲸鱼的呼唤
Summer night, ocean ​​paradise, whale calls.
不 不 白噪音很好
No, no. White noise is fine.
很好
Very well.
-晚安 Sox-晚安 巴兹
-Good night, Sox. -Good night, Buzz.
使突然终止
Pull up.
光年船长 你需要帮助吗？
Captain Lightyear, do you need help?
不 我能行
No. I can do it.
巴兹 你确定吗？
Buzz, are you sure?
恐怕这是礼节
I'm afraid it's protocol.
我能做到！
I can do it!
我能做到
I can do it.
审查表明你做了噩梦
Censors indicate you had a nightmare.
-你想谈谈吗-消极的
-Would you like to talk about it? -Negative.
好的 但请记住 我的任务是帮助你
Okay, but remember, my mission is to help you.
我不会放弃我的使命
And I'm not giving up on my mission.
是 啊
Yeah?
Yeah.
你知道吗 Sox 我也不会放弃我的使命
You know what, Sox, I'm not giving up on my mission either.
太棒了那我该怎么办？
Great! So what can I do?
好吧 你为什么不和你的鼠标伙伴打交道呢
Well, why won't you engage with your mouse buddy.
还有更具挑战性的吗？
Is there anything more challenging?
你想要挑战吗？可以
You want a challenge? Okay.
我想你可以研究一下燃料稳定性
I guess you could work on this fuel stability thing.
晶体熔合 当然
Crystalic fusion. Of course.
你什么时候回来？
When should I expect you back?
大约四年
About four years.
等等你不必这么做
Hold on. You don't have to do this.
指挥官 这是我的错误
Commander, this is my mistake.
我需要改正
I need to make it right.
好吧 但也许我们应该考虑一下
Okay, but maybe we should think about this.
想想什么？来吧 我们是太空流浪者
Think about what? Come on, we're Space Rangers.
我们完成了任务
We finish the mission.
嗯 如果能再穿上这套西装就好了
Well, it would be nice to wear the suit again.
人们开始忘记太空漫游者的重要性
People are starting to forget Space Rangers ever mattered.
好吧 我就要解决这个问题了
Well, I'm about to fix that.
无限大
To infinity.
甚至更远
And beyond.
不稳定
UNSTABLE
40周年快乐
HAPPY 40TH ANNIVERSARY
不稳定
UNSTABLE
嗨 巴兹
Hi, Buzz.
一两年后你就回来了
You're back here in a year or two...
好吧 我不会的
and, well, I won't.
我不知道什么时候发生的
I don't know when it happened
但我好像已经老了
but I seem to have gone and gotten very old.
我一直认为我们会再次成为太空流浪者
I always thought we'd get to be Space Rangers again.
我怀念在群星之中的日子
I miss being out among the stars.
所有的冒险
All the adventures.
但更重要的是
But more than any of that
我想念你
I missed you.
嗨 奶奶
Hi, Grandma.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, sweetheart.
我要给我的朋友巴兹留个口信
I'm leaving a message for my friend, Buzz.
太空漫游者？
The Space Ranger?
这是正确的
That's right.
他现在在太空
He's in space right now.
哇！
Wow.
这是我的孙女伊兹
This is my granddaughter, Izzy.
我也要成为一名太空护林员
I'm gonna be a Space Ranger too.
就像他一样？
Just like him?
就像你一样
Just like you.
再见 巴兹
Goodbye, Buzz.
很抱歉 我不能在那里看到你完成任务
I'm sorry I won't be there to see you finish the mission.
无限大
To infinity.
甚至更远
And beyond.
敲敲抱歉打断一下 我正要搬进我的新家-
Knock. Knock. Sorry to interrupt. I'm just moving into my new-
看那个！实际的巴斯光年
Look at that! The actual Buzz Lightyear in the flesh.
肯定的
Affirmative.
指挥官卡尔·伯恩赛德
Commander Cal Burnside.
我小时候是你的忠实粉丝
I was a big fan of your when I was a kid.
那么 我期待着与你合作 最终让我们离开这里
Well, then I look forward to working with you to finally get us out of here.
没人告诉你吗？
Did no one tell you?
告诉我什么？
Tell me what?
是 啊
Yeah.
这是最后一次任务 巴兹
That was the last mission, Buzz.
什么
What?
我们决定继续留在这里
We've decided we gonna go ahead and stay right here.
等等 在这儿？不 这不是一个可行的选择
Wait, here? Negative, that is not a viable option.
现在是 看 我们正在建造这个
It is now. See, we're building this.
激光屏蔽
Laser shield.
它会把所有的骗子都挡在外面
It'll keep all the creeters out.
我们就在这里吃点东西 用我们的东西凑合一下
And we'll just tuck right in here and make do with what we've got.
凑合吗？不 等等 但你不明白 指挥官
Make do? No. Wait. But you don't understand, Commander.
我仍然可以做到 我可以带我们离开这里
I can still do it. I can get us outta here.
伙计 你仍然相信这一点真是太好了
Man, it's great you still believe that.
但是我们很好 巴兹
But we're good, Buzz.
拿到激光防护罩
Got the laser shield.
哦你好 巴兹
Oh. Hello, Buzz.
嗡嗡声
Buzz?
嗯 我有个好消息 巴兹
Well, I've got some good news, Buzz.
我解决了燃料问题
I figured out the fuel problem.
什么
What?
这是一个有趣的组合
It was an interesting combination.
只是一点点的变化 但这一切都不同了
Just the slightest variance, but that made all the difference.
Sox 你是怎么做到的？
Sox, how did you do this?
我花了62年零7个月零5天
It took me 62 years, seven months and five days.
它是稳定的？
And it's stable?
理论上
Theoretically.
我期待着了解你的下一个任务
I look forward to finding out on your next mission.
是 啊
Yeah...
什么
What?
晚上好 船长 我们是来接你的同伴机器人的
Evening, Captain. We're here to pick up your companion robot.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
安全目的 你明白
Security purposes. You understand.
不 事实上 我没有
No, actually, I don't.
关闭程序 所以我们必须让你的猫退役
Shutting down the program, So, we have to decommission your cat.
只需要一秒钟
It'll just take a second.
现在 等等 只是
Now, hold on, just...
至少让我做吧
At least let me do it.
哇？
Whoa?
嗡嗡声我们要去哪里？
Buzz. Where are we going?
我们要去太空
We're going to space.
什么
What?
巴斯光年任务日志 明星日期
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date...
我不知道
I have no idea.
拥有稳定的燃料配方
In possession of stable fuel formula
我计划达到超高速 这次终于完成了任务
I plan to reach hyper-speed and this time finally finish the mission.
你在跟谁说话？
Who are you talking to?
没关系
Doesn't matter.
Buzz 我的程序迫使我通知Star司令部你已经走了--
Buzz, my programming compels me to notify Star Command that you have gone--
星际司令部本来打算让你退役的
Star Command was gonna decommission you.
-什么-这是正确的
-What? -That's right.
熄灯 不再有Sox
Lights out. No more Sox.
嘿你无权进入这个区域--
Hey! You're not authorized to be in this area--
哇 我不知道你能做到
Whoa, I didn't know you could do that.
等一下 这是给我的 以防我越界吗？
Wait a minute, was that for me in case I got out of line?
我给你五分钟
I bought you five minutes.
-好吧 Sox 给我第一个-罗杰
-All right, Sox, give me the first one. -Roger.
好了 开始了
Okay, here it goes.
哇！
Wow.
公式！
The formula!
探戈到基地 探戈到基地 发射桩的安全漏洞
Tango to Base. Tango to Base. Security breach in the launch peg.
爆炸
Blast.
我们有戒备 重复我们有戒备
We have a guard down. Repeat. We have a guard down.
可以
Okay.
你好
Hello.
-我是你的内部声控导航器-不一、 V.A.N ！不
-I'm your internal voice-activated navigator. -No! I.V.A.N.! No.
-你听到了吗-叫我I.V.A.N
-Do you hear that? -Call me I.V.A.N.
任务控制 在XL-15中检测到活动
Mission Control, activity detected in XL-15.
调查
Investigating.
收到
Roger that.
XL-15 这是控制器
XL-15, this is the control.
里面有人吗？
Is there someone in there?
-说点什么-XL-15
-Say something. -XL-15.
请回复
Please respond.
复制 控制 只是清洁人员
Copy, control. Just... the cleaning crew.
我们正在清理驾驶舱 清洁这里的物品？
We're cleaning the cockpit. Cleaning items in here?
指挥官 我们授权清洁XL-15的驾驶舱了吗？
Commander, did we authorize the cockpit cleaning for the XL-15?
什么不
What? No.
-住手！回来-等待
-Stop! Come back! -Wait!
XL-15 你违反了Star命令协议
XL-15, you are in violation of Star Command protocol.
立即停止行动
Cease your actions immediately.
打开这个舱门！
Open this hatch!
指挥官 我是光年船长
Commander, it's Captain Lightyear.
等待什么光年？把他弄出去！
Wait? What? Lightyear? Get him out of there!
马上停下 把手放在头上！
Stop right now and put your hands over your head!
支持
Back up.
-我们需要支援-找Zap巡逻队
-We need back up. -Get the Zap patrol.
好的 团队 走吧
All right, team. Let's go.
覆盖筒仓门 他哪儿也不去
Override the silo doors. He isn't going anywhere.
爆炸
Blast.
未经授权
Unauthorized.
-未经授权-来吧 我们在这里坐以待毙
-Unauthorized. -Come on, we're sitting ducks here.
请允许我
Allow me.
-等等 发生什么事了-他推翻了我的否决
-Wait, what's happening? -He overrode my override.
怎样
How?
光年！
Lightyear!
我知道你能听到我
I know you can hear me.
立即将船返回基地！
Return the ship to base right now!
或者帮帮我--
Or so help me--
Sox 让我们打破这个超高速障碍 让每个人都回家
Sox, let's break this hyper-speed barrier and get everyone home.
接近70%的超高速
Approaching 70 percent hyper-speed.
接近80%的超高速
Approaching 80 percent hyper-speed.
燃油稳定
Fuel stable.
90%超高速
Ninety percent hyper-speed.
100%超高速
One hundred percent hyper-speed.
祝贺你 光年船长
Congratulations, Captain Lightyear.
你已经实现了超高速
You have achieved hyper-speed.
我们做到了 Sox 我们做到了！
We did it. Sox, we did it!
祝贺你 巴兹
Congratulations, Buzz.
那太可怕了 我很后悔加入你们
That was utterly terrifying, and I regret having joined you.
不 不
No, no.
怎么了 巴兹？
What is it, Buzz?
我们的速度仍然非常高
Our velocity is still extremely high.
什么哦 不！
What? Oh no!
我们要撞车吗？
Are we gonna crash?
不
No.
嗯 从技术上讲是的 坚持住
Well, technically yes. Just hang on.
这么多年过去了 谢谢你 Sox
After all these years. Thank you, Sox.
任务日志 补充
Mission log, supplemental.
从星际司令部借了一艘船后 我实现了超高速
After borrowing a ship from Star Command I've achieved hyper-speed.
我终于准备好永远离开这个星球了
And I'm ready to finally leave this planet once and for all.
巴斯光年到恒星司令部 请进 星司令部
Buzz Lightyear to Star Command. Come in, Star Command.
星司令部 请进
Star Command, come in.
他们为什么不回答？
Why don't they answer?
嘿
Hey!
机器人
The robots.
什么？
The what?
机器人
The robots.
等等 它在做什么？
Wait, what's it doing?
扎尔格
Zurg.
-我的船-保持安静
-My ship! -Be quiet.
它去哪儿了？
Where'd it go?
在那里
Up there.
扎尔格
Zurg.
飞行员在哪里？
Where is the pilot?
那是什么？怎么回事？
What is that? What is going on?
使沮丧
Get down.
射击来吧
Shoot! Come on.
他们一定也看到你的船降落了
They must have seen your ship land too.
-谁-机器人
-Who? -The robots.
为什么会有机器人？这些机器人是从哪里来的？
Why are there robots? Where did the robots come from?
你从哪里来？
Where did you come from?
我是从这里来的
I came from here.
在这里等待
Here? Wait.
嗡嗡声
Buzz?
Alisha？
Alisha?
哦 不 那是我奶奶 我是伊兹
Oh, no, that's my grandmother. I'm Izzy.
伊兹？
Izzy?
但你只是有点
But you were just a little...
Sox 我们离开多久了？
Sox, how long were we gone?
喵喵
Meow meow.
22年19周零4天
Twenty-two years, 19 weeks and four days.
哇！
Wow.
等待
Wait.
来吧
Come on.
在这里
In here.
我想我听到了一个
I thought I heard one.
-机器人-是 啊
-A robot? -Yeah.
给人印象深刻的
Impressive.
嗯 我是霍桑
Well, I am a Hawthorne.
你当然是
You sure are.
你知道 你奶奶和我几乎可以完成对方的句子
You know, your grandma and I could practically finish each other's sentences.
如果你跟她一样 你和我会--
If you're anything like her, you and I are gonna make--
-...一个伟大的团队 -   有些机器人哭了
-...a great team. -...some robots cry.
可以
Okay...
所以 让我尽快了解这一点
So, get me up to speed on this.
正当Zurg船大约一周前出现
Right. The Zurg ship showed up about a week ago.
Zurg是什么？
What's a Zurg?
这是机器人唯一说的话 所以这就是我们所说的大船
That's the only thing the robots say, so that's what we call the big ship.
Zurg飞船抵达 机器人包围了基地 然后
The Zurg ship arrived, the robots surrounded the base, and then...
T'kani Prime的公民 外星人机器人已经攻击
Citizens of T'kani Prime, robot aliens have attacked.
周围的所有人
Everyone inside the perimeter.
留神
Look out!
我们正在立即启动激光屏蔽
We are activating the laser shield immediately.
这是我们最后一次听到
And that's the last we heard.
所有这些人都指望着我
All these people, they were counting on me.
现在他们被困住了
And now they're trapped.
我们试着联系他们 但没有任何沟通 无论是内部还是外部
We've tried to reach them, but there's no communication, in or out.
Sox？
Sox?
喵喵 她是对的
Meow meow. She's correct.
你检查过我和你的猫吗？
Did you check me against your cat?
嗯 他不是你的标准问题猫
Well, he's not your standard-issue feline.
事实上 Sox是你祖母送给你的礼物
Actually, Sox was a gift from your grandmother.
-你好 伊兹-你好 Sox
-Hello, Izzy. -Hello, Sox.
嘿 那是什么声音？来吧 别弄坏我的猫
Hey, what's that noise? Come on, don't break my cat.
他在呼噜呼噜 他喜欢它
He's purring. He likes it.
Sox 你喜欢吗？
Sox, do you like it?
我愿意
I do.
好吧 我希望你准备好行动了 因为我们只需要一个飞行员
Well, I hope you're ready for action. Because all we needed was a pilot.
为了什么？
For what?
我有一个计划 我有一个团队
I have a plan and I have a team.
来吧
Come on!
好了 队员们 请进
All right, team, fall in.
我找到了一个飞行员 惊喜行动派对很成功
I found a pilot. Operation Surprise Party is a go.
我喜欢这个 精英阵容 最好中的最好
I like this. An elite squad. The best of the best.
你知道 她的祖母是美国陆军历史上最伟大的太空护林员
You know, her grandmother was the greatest Space Ranger in the history of the Corps.
很荣幸能与您合作
It will be an honor to work with you.
来吧 大家围起来
Come on, gather round, team.
让我们回顾一下我们的目标
Let's review our objectives.
杀死机器人
Kill the robots.
不要死
And don't die.
“不死”只是你每天都想做的事
"Don't die" is just something you wanna do every day.
这仍然是一个目标
It's still an objective.
如果可以的话 我们有一个目标
If I may, we have one objective.
我们需要把这个水晶放在萝卜里 然后离开这里
We need to put this crystal in the turnip and get outta here.
所以 要做到这一点 我们必须进入基地
So, to do that we have to get onto the base.
要做到这一点 我们必须杀死所有的机器人
To do that we have to kill all the robots.
要做到这一点 我们必须摧毁Zurg飞船
To do that we have to destroy the Zurg ship.
要做到这一点 我们必须不死
And to do any of that we have to not die.
德里克
DERIC
请允许我解释一下“惊喜行动”晚会
Allow me to explain Operation Surprise Party.
这是“雷矛行动”的变体
It is a variation on Operation Thunder Spear.
你不是因为那件事获得了奖牌吗？
Didn't you get a medal for that one?
实际上是两个 但是
Two, actually, but...
等等 你怎么知道雷矛行动？
Wait, how do you know about Operation Thunder Spear?
我从头到尾都读过我奶奶的太空护林员的书
I've read all my grandma's Space Ranger books, from cover to cover.
两次
Twice.
对不起 机器猫
Excuse me, robot kitty.
哦 对不起
Oh, sorry.
传感器显示 Zurg飞船为地面机器人提供动力
Sensors have indicated that the Zurg ship powers the robots on the ground.
所以 我们飞到那里 炸了船 令人惊讶的是 机器人！
So, we fly up there, we blow up the ship. And surprise, robots!
你是土司
You're toast.
然后 我们把你的水晶放在萝卜里
Then, we put your crystal in the turnip.
完成任务
And finish the mission.
这是一个好计划 无限大
It's a good plan. To infinity.
你想让我拉你的手指吗？
Are you trying to get me to pull your finger?
不要上当
Don't fall for it.
不 不是那样的 是
No, not like that, it was...
对不起 这是我和你奶奶过去常做的事
Sorry, it's a thing your grandma and I used to do.
电子战
Ew.
我——我们从来没有——她不是有意的
I-- We were never-- She didn't mean to...
不管怎样 算了吧 继续
Anyway, forget it. Moving on.
让我们把这些弹药装进犰狳
Let's load these munitions into the Armadillo
为战斗而坚强
and steel ourselves for combat.
惊喜行动派对开始了
Operation Surprise Party is on.
巴兹 你听到了吗？
Buzz, do you hear that?
我听到一些声音
I hear something.
你觉得是机器人吗？
You think it's a robot?
不 我们从来没有在离基地这么远的地方见过机器人
Nah, we've never seen a robot this far from the base.
我什么也没听到
I don't hear anything.
现在我知道了
Now I do.
扎尔格
Zurg.
别担心 我们找到你了
Don't worry, we got you.
什么
What?
训练弹药
TRAINING AMMO
不要害怕！初级巡逻队支持你
Fear not! The Junior Patrol has your back.
少年什么？
The Junior what?
不船！
No! The ship!
我拿到了吗？
Did I get it?
非常接近
Pretty close.
对不起 我没有受过这种武器的训练
Sorry, I'm not trained with this weapon.
让我重新加载
Let me reload.
没有受过训练？等等 你说你“没有受过训练”是什么意思？
Not trained? Wait, what do you mean you're "not trained"?
你在那里 抓住它！抓住它！
You there. Grab it! Grab it!
抓住什么？
Grab what?
我不能拿武器
I'm not allowed to handle weapons
违反我的假释
the violation of my parole.
假释
Parole?
嗡嗡声
Buzz!
伊兹！现在
Izzy! Now!
不
No!
好的 新计划
Okay, new plan.
新计划？旧计划是什么？
New plan? What was the old plan?
我需要——有人看到鱼叉了吗？
I need the-- Anyone seen the harpoons?
他们预装了鱼叉 但我找不到--
They came preloaded with a harpoon, but I can't find--
哦 我找到了
Oh, I found it.
我找到了鱼叉 我现在要重新加载 看看这个
I found the harpoons. I'm gonna reload it now. Check this out.
我拿到了吗？
Did I get it?
往左边一点
A little to the left.
什么
What?
我拿到了吗？
Did I get it?
你明白了
You got it.
对
Yes!
繁荣
Boom.
好的 好的 到底是怎么回事--
Okay, okay. What exactly-- How did that--
你是谁？
Who are you?
我们是初级巡逻队 随时为您服务
We're the Junior Patrol, at your service.
好的 我需要更多的信息
Right, I'm gonna need more information.
我们是一支由自我激励的学员组成的志愿者团队
We are a volunteer team of self-motivated cadets.
我们在前哨站一个月训练一周
We train one week in a month here at the outpost.
莫、达比和我是上周末第一个到达的
Mo and Darby and I were the first to arrive last weekend
当机器人出现时
when the robots showed up.
所以 我们策划了“惊喜行动”派对
So, we cooked up Operation Surprise Party.
那么 你是新手？
So, you are rookies?
伙计 我们很想成为新人 还在努力
Boy, we'd love to be rookies, still building up to that.
可以你受过弹药训练吗？
Okay. Do you have munitions training?
-部分-战术交战？
-Partial. -Tactical engagement?
-待定-战斗经验？
-Pending. -Combat experience?
对如果你计算一下我们刚刚经历的机器人情况
Yes! If you count the robot situation we just went through.
可以来吧 Sox
Okay. Come on, Sox.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
看 你们看起来是好人
Look, you seem nice people.
我非常支持你的培训计划
I'm very supportive of your training initiatives.
但我会继续从这里开始
But I'm gonna go ahead and take it from here.
我们刚刚从那个机器人那里救了你
We just saved you from that robot.
-打扰一下-莫打出了致命一击
-Excuse me? -Mo made the kill shot.
莫很幸运
Mo got lucky.
非常
Very.
所以 如果你能告诉我另一艘船的方向
So, if you could just point me in the direction of another ship.
废弃的仓库里有正在运行的航天器
There are operational spacecrafts at the abandoned storage depot.
太棒了那是哪里？
Great. Where is that?
仓库与资源重组中心直接相邻
The storage depot is directly adjacent to the Resource Reconstituting Center,
距离你现在的位置4.2公里
which is 4.2 kilometers from your current location.
太棒了那是哪里？
Great. Where is that?
其实很简单
It's actually quite simple.
可以
Okay.
你将首先向南驶向基地
You will first head south towards the base.
两个停车灯后 您将--
After two stop lights you will--
等等 这不对 这是一条死胡同
Wait, that is not right. That is a dead end.
哦 我明白了 我找错地方了
Oh, I see, I was in the wrong spot.
道歉 我会重新开始
Apologies. I will start over.
你将首先向南驶向基地
You will first head south towards the base.
在两个停车灯后 你将温和地向左转--
After two stop lights you'll take a gentle left and--
射击我又犯了一个错误
Shoot. I have made another error.
我们只给你看看
We'll just show you.
请允许我重新开始
Allow me to restart.
你将首先向南驶向基地
You will first head south towards the base.
在两个停车灯后 你将向右急转弯
After two stop lights you'll take a hard right...
巴斯光年补充任务日志
Buzz Lightyear supplemental mission log.
最终实现超高速
Having finally achieved hyper-speed
我现在遇到了另一个障碍
I now have an additional obstacle in my way.
为了逃离这个星球 我必须独自摧毁一艘巨大的外星飞船
In order to flee this planet I'll have to destroy a massive alien ship alone.
没有任何帮助
with no assistance of any kind.
你知道 我们可以帮你 这是我们的计划
You know, we can help you. It is our plan.
我不能允许那样
I can't allow that.
Star命令代码2709.3
Star Command Code 2709.3
禁止我将不合格的人员置于危险的地方
forbids me from placing unqualified personnel in harms way.
好吧 但我是霍桑
Okay, but I'm a Hawthorne.
这不仅仅是一个名字 伊兹
It's more than just a name, Izzy.
你必须确切地知道--
You have to know exactly--
-...在任何坐姿中如何反应--   你接下来要说什么
-...how to react in any sit-- -...what you gonna say next.
我以为我有那个
I thought I had that one.
可以
Okay.
而你 你正处于某种矫正状态？
And you, you're in a correctional situation of some kind?
假释计划
Parole program.
我这样做了 他们从我的句子中删掉了一点时间
I do this and they shave a little time off my sentence.
但我在那里学到了很多
But I really learned a lot in there.
达比可以拿走任何三样东西 然后让它们爆炸
Darby can take any three things and make them explode.
可以那你呢？
Okay. And what about you?
我我以为这会是一个有趣的训练营锻炼
Me? I thought this was gonna be like a fun boot camp workout thing.
但事实并非如此
But it is not.
所以 我实际上是来这里交我的东西的--
So, I was actually coming out here to turn in my stuff--
他是个半途而废的人
He's a quitter.
我不是一个半途而废的人
I'm not a quitter.
你要退出
You were quitting.
你在说什么？我只是往另一个方向走
What are you talking about? I was just going in a different direction.
是的 一个放弃者的方向
Yeah, the direction of a quitter.
你知道吗 我放弃了
You know what, I give up.
-看到了吗-在你的右边
-See? -On your right..
扎尔格
Zurg.
现在 我在哪里？
Now, where was I?
我们到了 让我退一步
Here we are. Let me back up.
嘿 继续练习你的技能 这是变得更好的唯一途径
Hey, keep working on your skills. It's the only way to get better.
我们可以帮助你
We can help you.
我很感激 回到你的训练设施
And I appreciate that. Just go back to your training facility.
保持警惕 保持安全
Stay alert. Stay safe.
我要征用这只P-32犰狳
I'm going to commandeer this P-32 Armadillo
然后炸毁Zurg飞船
and go blow up the Zurg ship.
那么 这只是再见？
So, this is just goodbye?
肯定的再见
Affirmative. Goodbye.
对不起 我忘了带我的猫
Sorry, I forgot my cat.
检测到生命形式
Life forms detected.
它们是什么？
What are they?
巨大的昆虫类生物
Giant insectoid organisms.
这座建筑看起来像个蜂巢
The building appears to be some sort of hive.
他们是威胁吗？
Are they a threat?
传感器显示它们正在休眠
Sensors indicate they are hibernating.
非常好
Very good.
哦 看！
Oh, look!
这是XL-01
It's the XL-01.
很久没有
It's been a long time since...
哇
Whoa.
这是怎么一回事？
What is it?
来吧 我给你看看
Come on, I'll show you.
最后
Finally.
抱歉打断一下
Sorry to interrupt.
看起来你过得很愉快
Looks like you were having a real nice moment.
你在这里干什么？这不安全
What are you doing here? It's not safe.
你拿走了我们卡车的钥匙
You took the keys to our truck.
他们在那里
There they are.
来吧来吧
Come on. Come on.
-安静-我正在努力
-Quiet. -I'm trying.
知道了
Got it.
-有人去——-去开门！
-Somebody get-- -Get the door!
你说“开门” 我就开门了
You were gonna say "get the door", and I got the door.
好吧 我要直截了当地说 我希望那没有发生
Well, I'm gonna be blunt here. I wish that hadn't happened.
我们其他人也是
So did the rest of us.
每个人都拿起武器
Everyone grab a weapon.
孩子 我很想 但是我的假释--
Boy, I'd love to, but my parole--
作为一名星际指挥官 我授予你紧急权力
As a Star Command Officer I grant you emergency authority.
我们要赶紧离开这里
We're gonna blast our way outta here.
现在我们在说话！
Now we're talking!
Buzz 正面攻击的存活概率为38.2%
Buzz, the probability of survival a frontal attack is 38.2 percent.
看起来有点低
Seems a bit low.
隐形模式呢？
What about Stealth Mode?
你怎么知道隐形模式？
How do you know about Stealth Mode?
我和奶奶过去一直玩隐形模式
Grandma and I used to play Stealth Mode all the time.
这就像捉迷藏 但有一个转折
It was like hide-and-seek, but with a twist.
好吧 其实这是个好主意 我会用隐形模式来迷惑他们
Okay, well, it's actually good thinking. I'll use Stealth Mode to disorient them.
或者 和我在一起
Or, and stick with me here.
我们都可以使用隐形模式 然后直接离开
We could all use Stealth Mode and just walk right out.
你是说 你会穿太空护林服？
You mean, you would wear a Space Ranger suit?
这个上面已经有我的名字了
This one already has my name on it.
可以
Okay.
让我们回顾一下
Let's review.
我要走了--
I'm going--
那样的话
That way.
你要走了--
And you're going--
那样的话
That way.
可以非常好
Okay. Very good.
看看 我是Feathers   羽化
Check it out, I'm Feathers... Feathering...
哦 看 一支钢笔 凉的
Oh, look, a pen. Cool.
-你的有钢笔吗-好的 注意
-Does yours have a pen? -Okay, pay attention.
隐形模式相当简单
Stealth mode is fairly simple.
只有两部分 你按下按钮--
There are just two parts. You press the button--
-是这个按钮吗-我会告诉你哪个按钮
-Is it this button? -I will tell you which button.
-这个按钮怎么样-我很抱歉
-What about this button? -I'm sorry.
我们没有时间检查所有的按钮
We're not gonna have time to go over all the buttons.
好吧 忘记按钮 这件事怎么办？
Okay, forget the button. What about this thing?
-它更…-不！不
-It's more-- -No! No!
这就是投降链 你永远不会那样做
That's the surrender strand. You never pull that.
对于太空巡游者来说 再也没有比这更可耻的动作了
There is no more shameful maneuver for a Space Ranger.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我错过了哪个按钮是隐形模式按钮了吗？
Did I miss which button is the Stealth Mode button?
是这个按钮
It's this button.
还没有！
Not yet!
你按下这个按钮 然后走出前门
You push this button, then you go out the front door,
我去炸毁Zurg飞船
and I'll go blow up the Zurg ship.
-准备好了吗-准备好的
-Ready? -Ready.
不 等等 没有准备好 坚持
No, wait. Not ready. Hang on.
好的 明白了 那会很尴尬的
Okay, got 'em. That would've been embarrassing.
可以
Okay.
再见
Goodbye again.
Sox 你在抑制我的视觉
Sox, you're inhibiting my visual.
很抱歉这样更好吗？
Sorry. Is this better?
-否定-好的 这个怎么样？
-Negative. -Okay, how about this?
这个怎么样？
How about this?
可以我们开始吧
Okay. Here we go.
非常好 隐形模式按计划工作
Very good. Stealth Mode working as planned.
这很酷 这些愚蠢的虫子甚至看不见我们
This is pretty cool. These dumb bugs can't even see us.
嘿bug 嘿bug 缺陷
Hey, bug. Hey, bug. Bug.
我就在这里 巴格 你看不见我吗？
I'm right here, bug. Can't you see me?
他不能 他根本看不到我
He can't. He can't see me at all.
时间已经过去了
And time has elapsed.
等等 计时器
Wait, the timer.
他们不知道计时器
They don't know about the timer.
你看不到我
You don't see me.
等待我能看见你
Wait. I can see you.
我也能看到你
I can see you too.
虫子可以看到我们
The bugs can see us.
不 不 我投降了
No, no. I surrender.
拉
Pull!
返回返回
Back! Back!
这不起作用
This isn't working.
你必须继续前进！
You have to keep going!
我们必须回头
We have to turn around.
他们正向我们走来
They're headed right for us.
不 不 不要靠近车辆！
No, no. Do not approach the vehicle!
好吧
All right!
-适应的方式 团队-在这里放弃吧
-Way to adapt, team. -Give it up here.
你为什么要祝贺自己？
Why are you congratulating yourselves?
因为我刚刚把我们从那种情况下拖了出来
Because I just Hawthorned us out right outta that situation.
但如果你能做到的话--
But you could've made it if--
如果你告诉我们隐形模式会消失
If you had told us the Stealth Mode wears off.
好
Well...
好的 大家都系好安全带
Okay, everyone just strap in.
你好 我是你的--
Hello, I am your--
等等
Hold on!
我们要去太空吗？
Are we going to space?
不 我要把你送到某个地方
No, I'm gonna drop you somewhere.
那是一个巨大的旋转 我想我需要一个袋子
That was a big swirly turn. I think I need a bag.
不 不 不要在车内呕吐
No, no. Do not vomit inside the vehicle.
我能看到开始 这就是空间
I can see starts. That is space.
现在发生了什么？
What is happening right now?
她害怕空间
She's afraid of space.
-什么-她应该是 太可怕了
-What? -She should be. It's horrible
伊兹 记住你的练习
Izzy, remember your exercises.
-它来了-不 不
-It's coming. -No, no.
戴上头盔 那会抓住它的
Engage your helmet. That will catch it.
-巴斯！另一艘船-伊兹 我在努力--
-Buzz! Another ship! -Izzy, I'm trying--
我什么也看不见
I can't see anything.
哦 不！行星的黑暗面
Oh, no! The dark side of the planet.
在那边三点钟！
Over there! Three o'clock!
等等这可不好看
Hold on. This isn't gonna be pretty.
大家都还好吗？
Is everyone okay?
我认为是这样
I think so.
Sox 给我一份损失报告
Sox, give me a damage report.
请稍等
One moment, please.
可以这样更好
Okay. This is better.
这样更好吗？
Is this better?
不 显然总体来说情况更糟 我只是说   你知道的
No, obviously this is worse overall, I just meant... You know...
你怎么害怕太空？
How are you afraid of space?
哦 这很容易
Oh, It's pretty easy.
你知道如果你放手 你就会一直朝着同一个方向走吗
Did you know if you let go out there you just keep going in the same direction
永远 只是
forever, just...
那你打算怎么炸毁Zurg号？
Well, then how were you going to blow up the Zurg ship?
我会成为地面支援
I would've been ground support.
我知道 奶奶不害怕空间
I know, grandma wasn't afraid of space.
不 因为她是一名太空护林员
No, because she was a Space Ranger.
天体恐惧症是一种自动取消资格
Astrophobia is an automatic disqualification.
那是什么？
What was that thing?
-我不知道-它会回来吗？
-I don't know. -Is it gonna come back?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是它是怎么做到的——好吧 你不知道
But how did it-- Okay, you don't know.
我完了 我终于拿到了水晶 这本该结束的
I was done. I finally had the crystal. This was supposed to be over.
但我在跟谁开玩笑？
But who am I kidding?
我不需要水晶
I don't need a crystal.
我需要一台时间机器来摆脱这场混乱
I need a time machine to get out of this mess.
评估完成
Assessment complete.
这有多糟糕？
How bad is that?
爆炸被隔热板吸收 只引起轻微的电气短路
The blast was absorbed by the heat shield and only caused a minor electrical short.
可以
Okay.
因此 为了使飞行正常运行
So, in order to be flight operational
犰狳需要一种具有特殊电容的材料
the Armadillo will require a material of specialized capacitance.
哦 就像一个电子的东西
Oh, like an electrical thingy.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know that?
我们学到了这一点
We learned this.
专业电容 记得吗？我们上个月造了那些野外无线电？
Specialized capacitance, remember? We built those field radios last month?
哦 是的 这很有趣
Oh, yeah. That was fun.
是的 除了Darby把她搞砸了
Yeah, except Darby messed hers up.
我会把你搞砸的--
I'm gonna mess you up--
请我试着在这里思考
Please. I'm trying to think here.
我把我的搞砸了 但后来我把它修好了
I messed mine up, but then I fixed it up.
但是你把电脑控制台弄坏了
But you broke that computer console.
我需要那个小线圈来   那是什么？
I needed that little coil for its... What was that?
专用电容
Specialized capacitance.
嘿 老实说 这里有很大的空间
Hey, honestly, there is a lot of room out here.
如果你们想回忆 可以去那里
If you guys wanna reminisce you could go over there,
或者你看 没有人在那里思考
or look, there's no one trying to think over there.
我们可以上去
We can go up there.
好的完美的
Fine. Perfect.
对好的 新计划
Yes. Okay, new plan.
等待什么
Wait. What?
那个采矿设施将有一个控制台 对吗？
That mining facility will have a console, right?
那个控制台会有一个小线圈 对吗？
That console will have a little coil thing, right?
那个小线圈会有
And that little coil thing will have the...
专用电容
Specialized capacitance.
我们需要修理这艘船 对吗？
That we need to fix this ship, right?
她是对的
She's right.
干得好这就像霍桑一样思考
Good job. Now that's thinking like a Hawthorne.
我们去拿那部分然后离开这里
Let's go get that part and get outta here
在那东西再次找到我们之前
before that thing finds us again.
哇
Whoa.
在那边
Over there.
好了 我们开始吧
Okay, here we go.
巴斯光年任务日志
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
为了修理我们的船 我们必须想办法
In order to repair our ship we have to find some way
进入指挥中心
to get inside the Command Center and...
干得好 老囚犯
Nice job, elderly convict.
好的 激活线圈应该在这里
Okay, the activation coil should be in here.
Sox？
Sox?
需要钢笔吗？
Need a pen?
知道了
Got it.
好的 是的 下次
Okay, yeah. Another time.
哦 不
Oh no.
安全措施已激活
Security measures activated.
不不要再这样了
No! Not this again.
不是什么？这是什么？
Not what? What is this?
捕获锥 直到他们来抓你
A capture cone. That holds you until they come and get you.
没有人来接我们 他们都被困在基地里
No one's coming to get us. They're all trapped in the base.
所以 我们应该离开 对吗？
So, we should just leave, right?
我们不能就这样离开
We can't just leave.
当然可以 从我这里拿走吧 我们可以随时离开
Sure we can. Take it from me, we can always just leave.
看 看到了吗？
Look, see?
来吧
Come on!
告诉你了
Told you.
现在 小心点 因为这些东西--
Now, be careful, because these things--
如果它们接触 则合并
combine if they touch.
好吧 对不起 但如果我们都试一下的话？
All right, sorry. But maybe if we both try it?
这行不通
That's not gonna work.
你甚至都没试过
You haven't even tried.
不
No!
喵
Meow.
是的 那没用
Yeah, that didn't work.
-Buzz-等等
-Buzz? -Whoa, hold on.
如果我和你在一起 我对任何人都没有帮助
I'm no help to anyone if I'm stuck in there with you.
Sox 你能把这些关掉吗？
Sox, can you turn these off?
我够不到控制装置
I can't reach the controls.
等等 地板上有个软点
Wait, there's a soft spot in the floor here.
-也许如果我们能…-那是我的脚
-Maybe if we could-- -That's my foot.
-对不起-等等 看！
-Sorry. -Wait, watch it!
等等 就这样 那东西为这些东西提供动力
Wait, that's it. That thing powers these things.
-那我们再来一次-等待等待
-Then let's hit it again. -Wait. Wait.
我们需要开门
We need the door to be open.
所以我打开这个 你猛撞电源
So I'll open this. You slam into the power source.
这些东西会消失 我们马上就走
These things will disappear. And we'll walk right out.
-是的 先生-好吧
-Yes, sir. -All right.
准备好的
Ready?
继续努力！
Keep trying!
我们只是不够重
We're just not heavy enough.
巴斯 我们需要你
Buzz, we need you.
等等 在那里？
Wait, in there?
但如果它不起作用 我就救不了你
But if it doesn't work I won't be able to save you.
你不需要救我们 你需要加入我们
You don't need to save us, you need to join us.
再一次
Again.
Again!
再一次
不
No!
去去
Go! Go!
小心
Watch out!
巴斯 不！
Buzz, no!
我们需要线圈
We need the coil.
我们抓住你了
We got you.
哦 看 零食
Oh, look. Snacks.
有人要吃点心吗？
Anyone going for the snack?
肉三明治
MEAT SANDWICH
在这里让我们都重新充电一点
Here. Let's all re-charge a little.
干得好
Here you go.
这是什么--
Huh, this is, uh-- What-- What's--
这里发生了什么？
What's happening here?
你的三明治怎么了？
Something wrong with your sandwich?
为什么肉在外面？
Why is the meat on the outside?
因为它是三明治？
Because it's a sandwich?
不 面包应该在外面
No, the bread is supposed to be on the outside.
什么 像面包 肉 面包？
What, like, bread, meat, bread?
那面包太多了
That's too much bread.
是的 但这都是湿的
Yes, but this is all wet.
是 啊多汁的手指 这是最好的部分
Yeah. Juicy fingers. That's the best part.
你最后一次吃三明治是什么时候？
When was the last time you had a sandwich?
我不知道 一百年前 是给予还是索取
I don't know, a hundred years ago, give or take.
只是一个“面包 肉 面包 ”
Just a "bread, meat, bread."
那面包太多了
That's too much bread.
那只会把你嘴里的水分都吸出来
That would just suck all the moisture out of your mouth.
很好 达比
Good one, Darby.
哦 不！
Oh, no!
Sox！
Sox!
醒醒 Sox
Wake up, Sox.
来吧 小朋友 回到我身边
Come on, little buddy, come back to me.
求你了 Sox 我很抱歉
Please, Sox. I'm sorry.
Sox
Sox.
你好我需要重新启动
Hello. I require a reboot.
对不起 伙计们 我差点杀了Sox
I'm sorry, guys. I almost killed Sox.
我差点把我们都杀了
I almost got us all killed back there.
嘿 听我说 这只是个错误
Hey, listen to me, it was just a mistake.
对吧 巴兹？
Right, Buzz?
试着好一点
Just try to get a little better.
听
Listen.
我只是
I just...
当我第一次去学院的时候我不是   你知道的   好的
When I first went to the Academy I was not... you know... good.
我每天都搞砸了
I screwed up every day.
我被障碍物缠住了
I got tangled in the obstacle course.
我的手抖得厉害 打不中目标
My hands shook so much I couldn't hit the target.
不是靶心 整个目标
Not the bulls-eye. The whole target.
第一周后我就要辞职了 那是
And I was gonna quit after the first week, it was...
很明显我不是太空流浪者的材料
clear I was not Space Ranger material.
真正地
Really?
是 啊
Yeah.
但是她的奶奶看到了我的一些东西
But her grandma saw something in me.
所以我也开始找了
So I started looking for it too.
重新校准
Recalibrating.
已还原一个损坏的文件
One corrupted file restored.
嘿 他在点灯
Hey, he's lighting up.
-奶奶-你好 Sox
-Grandma. -Hello, Sox.
我需要你帮我一个忙
I need you to do me a favor.
我需要你照顾我最好的朋友 他的名字叫巴兹
I need you to look after my best friend. His name is Buzz.
他现在不在 但很快就会回来
He's away right now, but he'll be back soon.
他是一名太空护林员
He's a Space Ranger.
他会带我们回家的 把我们都带回家
He's going to get us all home. Get us all home.
发生了什么？
What's wrong?
你没听到吗？
Did not you hear that?
她相信我可以纠正我犯的错误
She believed I could fix the mistake I made.
这种信念让她付出了一切代价
And that belief cost her everything.
每件事不
Everything? No.
她有奶奶纪子 我爸爸和我 还有她所有的朋友
She had grandma Kiko, my Dad and me, all her friends.
她本不想在这里 但她在这个星球上度过了一生 巴斯
She didn't meant to be here, but she had a whole life on this planet, Buzz.
我们所有人都有
All of us had.
除了你
Except for you.
我们想再次成为太空流浪者 我们想变得重要
We wanted to be Space Rangers again. We wanted to matter.
相信我 她很重要
Believe me, she mattered.
你知道 这样很好
You know, it is pretty good this way.
是 啊面包 肉 面包 你这样干了多久？
Yeah? Bread, meat, bread. How long did you do it like that?
永远
Forever.
完全充电
Fully recharged.
来吧
Come on.
我们把这部分放到船上 然后离开这里
Let's go put this part in the ship and get outta here.
Sox 你能为我们引路吗？
Sox, can you light our way?
当然
Of course.
单击单击 单击单击
Click click. Click click.
我懂你 我会抓住你的 我会抓住你的
I see you. I'm gonna get ya. I'm gonna get ya.
哦 我没听懂
Oh, I didn't get ya.
-Sox-你去哪儿了？我抓住你了！
-Sox? -Where'd you go? I got you!
-Sox-是的 对不起
-Sox. -Yeah, sorry.
这很令人兴奋 惊喜行动派对 我们来了！
This is exciting. Operation Surprise Party, here we come!
等等 什么？消极的我不能那样伤害你
Wait, what? Negative. I can't put you in harm's way like that.
什么 你要一个人完成整个任务吗？
What, are you gonna do the whole mission alone?
我能做到
I can do it.
因为你这里有一棵山楂树
Because you got a Hawthorne right here.
我很感激 告诉你 如果我需要你 我会告诉你的
And I appreciate that. Tell you what, I'll let you know if I need you.
但在那之前 让我们试着不用再谈犰狳了--
But until then let's just try to get back to the Armadillo without any more--
跑
Run!
不
No!
什么
What?
它在追我！回船上去！
It's after me! Go back to the ship!
但是巴斯！
But Buzz!
巴斯光年任务日志
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
我被一个
I'm being pursued by a...
只是一个巨大的机器人
just a massive robot.
我把它带走 其他人逃到船上
I'm leading it away while the others escape to the ship.
嗡嗡声
Buzz.
什么你怎么知道我的名字？
What? How do you know my name?
跟我来
Come with me.
什么
What?
这绝对违反了我的假释
This is definitely a violation of my parole.
来吧让我们离开这里
Come on. Let's get outta here.
扎尔格
Zurg.
做好发射准备 惊喜行动又开始了
Ready yourselves for launch. Operation Surprise Party is back on.
什么和我们一起？
What? With us?
什么 我要独自完成整个任务吗？
What, am I gonna do the whole mission alone?
我们还不能发射 我需要五分钟来安装线圈
We can't launch yet. I need five minutes to install the coil.
我们不能在这里坐五分钟
We can't sit here for five minutes.
该船仍具有悬停能力
The ship still has hover capabilities.
那么让我们使用它们
Then let's use them.
我们可能会在火喷泉中失去他们
We might lose them in the fire geysers.
闪避一下 你们两个 炸掉一些机器人
Blink the way. You two, blast some robots.
但我们甚至还没有完成弹药训练
But we haven't even finished our munitions training.
这有多难？看
How hard can it be? Look.
我们有这些尖尖的东西 这些可能会爆炸
We got these spiky things. And these one probably explode.
做任何感觉合适的事
Just do whatever feels right.
什么你打算怎么办？
What? What are you gonna do?
我要和Boom先生跳舞
I'm gonna dance with Mister Boom.
现在这很令人满意
Now that's satisfying.
完成20%
Twenty percent complete.
百分之一百？
Out of a hundred?
他们在追我们 那些间歇喷泉在哪里？
They're gaining on us. Where are those fire geysers?
正前方
Dead ahead.
别担心 我知道每一寸--
Don't worry, I know every last inch of--
小心
Watch out!
给 扔这个
Here, throw this.
-等等 等等-扔出去！
-Wait, hold on. -Throw it!
扎尔格
Zurg.
前方有喷泉！
Fire geyser dead ahead!
完成50%
Fifty percent complete.
扎尔格
Zurg.
嘿 我们这里有炸药！
Hey, we have explosives back here!
快的给我点东西
Quick! Give me something.
扎尔格
Zurg.
完成90%
Ninety percent complete.
伊兹 你知道如何在飞行中转移能量吗？
Izzy, do you know how to transfer power on the fly?
我已经在模拟器中完成了
I've done it in the simulator.
嗯 它即将成为现实
Well, it's about to get real.
-你需要我帮忙吗-绝对不是
-Do you need my help with anything? -Absolutely not.
完成95%
Ninety five percent complete.
准备好的推进器 绿色按钮 中间的
Ready thrusters. Green button. Middle.
完成
Done.
从训练中记住
Remember from training.
你不扣动扳机 你扣动扳机
You don't pull the trigger, you squeeze the trigger.
我知道
I know.
完成99%
Ninety nine percent complete.
转换为振荡功率
Transfer to Oscillating Power.
完成
Done.
100%完成
One hundred percent complete.
重新启动 好的 准备好发射
Reboot. Okay, be ready to launch
当燃料电池--
when the fuel cell is--
不
No!
哦 不
Oh, no.
爆炸
Blast!
抓住水晶！
Grab the crystal!
不
No.
我
I...
嗡嗡声
Buzz.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
一切都发生得很快 我
Everything was happening so fast and I...
我只是
I just...
我犯了一个错误
I made a mistake.
是 啊
Yeah.
好吧 但我们还没结束 对吗？
Okay, but we're not done, right?
我们仍然可以做点什么
We can still do something.
伊兹 看看周围
Izzy, look around.
没什么可做的
There is nothing to do.
任务
The mission...
结束了
It's over.
嗡嗡声
Buzz.
Buzz!
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
我只需要一个人
I just need to be by myself.
不
No!
嗡嗡声
Buzz!
Buzz.
什么
What the...
这是什么？我们在哪里？
What is this? Where are we?
你是谁？
Who are you?
这就是问题所在
Now that's the question.
你看起来不错 巴兹
You look good, Buzz.
爸爸
Dad?
再猜猜看
Guess again.
Sox？
Sox?
你好 巴兹
Hello, Buzz.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我把这一切都搞砸了
I messed this all up.
嘿 这只是个错误
Hey, it was just a mistake.
记得你告诉我的吗？
Remember what you told me?
这个不同
This one's different.
为什么？
Why?
因为它是我的！
Because it's mine!
我应该和我奶奶一样好
I'm supposed to be as good as my grandma.
我应该是霍桑
I'm supposed to be a Hawthorne.
但我不是
But I'm not.
嗡嗡声
Buzz?
等等 等等
Wait a minute, hold on.
你不是我 我就是我
You're not me. I am me.
你现在就是你
You are you now.
但50年后我就是你了
But I'm you 50 years from now.
嗯 不可能有两个小微
Well, there can't be two mes.
然而 我们都在这里
Yet here we both are.
那好吧 如果你是我
Okay then. If you're me.
我在想一个介于1和之间的数字--
I'm thinking of a number between one and--
1273.
哇
Whoa.
扎尔格
Zurg.
真可爱
Isn't that cute.
机器人不会说“嗡嗡声”
Robots can't quite say "Buzz."
所以在这里我只是Zurg
So around here I'm just Zurg.
扎尔格
Zurg.
我想你也是
And I guess so are you.
怎样我不明白
How? I don't understand.
别担心 这些都无关紧要
Do not worry about it. None of this is gonna matter.
嗡嗡声
Buzz.
对
Yes?
你必须向他解释这一切
You have to explain it all to him.
你说得对
You're right.
对不起 这太令人兴奋了
I'm sorry, it's just exciting.
你终于来了
You're finally here.
看 我也达到了超高速
See, I reached hyper-speed too.
超高速
Hyper-speed.
就像你做的那样
Like you did.
但我并没有被当作英雄来迎接
But I wasn't greeted as a hero.
不 那个新指挥官要逮捕我 因为我偷了XL-15
No, that new Commander was gonna arrest me for stealing the XL-15.
我找到了让他们回家的方法 他们甚至都不在乎
I'd found a way to get them home, and they didn't even care.
所以我逃走了
So I escaped.
我尽我所能 尽我所能快
I went as far as I could, as fast as I could.
我以这种速度旅行了几个世纪
At that speed for that long I'd traveled centuries.
而我的未来你却认不出来
And I ended up in a future you wouldn’t recognize.
充满了你无法想象的技术
Filled with technology you can't imagine.
就在那时 我意识到了这一点
And that's when it dawned on me.
如果我们能用这块水晶及时前进
If we can use this crystal to go forward in time.
为什么不用它回去呢？
Why not use it to go back?
但我们不能回到过去
But we can't go back in time.
-我们现在可以了-什么
-We can now. -What?
听着 巴兹 我打破了时间
Listen, Buzz, I've broken time.
发生在你身上的事从来没有发生在我身上
What's happening to you never happened to me.
这是一个从未有过的新的现在
This is a new now that's never been lived.
你看 我们可以改变一切 巴兹
You see, we can change things, Buzz.
好吧 如果我们能回到过去 我们可以阻止自己
Well, if we can go back in time we can stop ourselves
从登陆那颗星球开始
from ever landing on that planet.
从那座山上下来
From ever hitting that mountain.
我们可以继续任务回家
We can just continue the mission home.
这一切都不会发生
And none of this will have ever happened.
这是一个好计划
it's a good plan.
这颗水晶是这一切的关键
And this crystal is the key to it all.
等等 你不是已经有了吗？
Wait, don't you already have one?
嗯 有点像
Well, sort of.
看 我戴着我的水晶去测试时间旅行
See, I wore my crystal out testing the time travel.
我也累坏了 这花了一段时间
Wore myself out too. It took a while.
事实证明这不是一门精确的科学
Turns out this isn't an exact science.
这是我能找到的最早的时间了
This is as far back in time as I could get.
来 帮我配置引擎
Come on, help me configure the engine.
它应该看起来很熟悉
It should look familiar.
等等 这是基于萝卜吗？
Wait, is this based on the turnip?
将其设置为反向推进器 满
Set it for reversed thrusters, full.
那么 我们设计了所有这些？
So, we designed all of this?
不 这都是借来的
No, this is all borrowed.
我只是做了一些修改
I just made some modifications.
她会再次成为太空护林员的 巴兹
She'll get to be a Space Ranger again, Buzz.
是 啊
Yeah.
虽然
Although...
什么
What?
嗯 她不会有她的家人
Well, she won't have her family.
她不会有伊兹
She won't have Izzy.
谁是伊兹？
Who's Izzy?
听着 她不会错过任何人的
Look, she's not gonna miss anyone
如果她一开始从未见过他们 对吗？
if she never meets them in the first place, right?
人们唯一知道的是我们完成了任务
The only thing people are gonna know is that we finished our mission.
在这里把你的水晶递给我
Here. Hand me your crystal.
嗡嗡声
Buzz?
我不知道 也许
I don't know, maybe...
也许我们应该考虑一下
maybe we should think about this.
想想什么？
Think about what?
霍桑指挥官相信我们可以纠正我们犯下的这个错误
Commander Hawthorne believed we could fix this mistake we made.
这种信念让她付出了一切代价
And that belief cost her everything.
哦 不 不 我们都错了
Oh, no, no. We had that all wrong.
她在那里度过了一生
She had a whole life down there.
什么样的生活？
What kind of life?
我们应该是太空流浪者
We're supposed to be Space Rangers.
我们应该很重要
We suppose to matter.
你不想这样生活 巴兹
You don't wanna live like this, Buzz.
醒来时也做了同样的噩梦
Waking up with that same nightmare.
被你的错误所困扰
Haunted by your mistake.
但你终于可以放下它了
But you can finally let go of that.
从现在开始
Starting right now.
你说得对
You're right.
我可以
I can.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
你和我 我们不一样
You and me, we're not the same.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不 巴兹
No, Buzz.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
嘿 猫
Hey, cat.
你知道怎么飞这东西吗？
Do you know how to fly this thing?
没有燃料了
There's no fuel.
看 这就是为什么我们永远不应该进入我们的头
See, this is why we should never have gotten in over our heads.
你想做什么？
What did you wanna do?
在前哨站等机器人找到我们？
Wait at the outpost until the robots found us?
这总比被困在这里好
That's better than being stranded out here.
没有人能找到我们
where no one's ever gonna find us.
你是我在生死关头最不想遇到的人
You are the last person I wanna be stuck with in a life-and-death situation.
嗯 你很幸运 可以
Well, you're in luck. Okay?
因为环顾四周 这只是一种死亡状态
Cause look around. This is just a death situation.
喵喵
Meow meow.
我完全失去了嗡嗡声
I've completely lost Buzz.
他太远了 无法追踪
He's too far away to track.
所有人 里面！
Everybody, inside!
什么
What?
进入船内
Get inside the ship.
我们现在在干什么？
What's after us now?
我们没有更多的武器了
We don't have any more weapons.
没关系 我们要离开这里
It's okay. We're getting out of here.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
我们要进入太空
We're going into space.
嘿 放开我 不
Hey, let go of me. No!
我不明白这里发生了什么 巴兹
I don't understand what's happening here, Buzz.
你变了
You've changed.
而且不是为了更好
And not for the better.
不
No!
你不能这样做 你要把它全部抹掉
You can't do this. You're gonna erase it all.
确切地
Exactly.
不 你要拿走一切
No, you gonna take away everything.
人们的家人 他们的朋友
People's families, their friends.
我的朋友们
My friends.
他们在那个星球上有生命
They have lives on that planet.
每个人都这样
Everyone does.
除了我们
Except for us.
我几乎认不出你了 巴兹
I hardly recognize you, Buzz.
所有这些新想法
All these new ideas...
你知道吗？
You know what?
我们将继续删除这些内容
We'll go ahead and erase those too.
-哇-我给你五分钟
-Whoa. -I bought you five minutes.
为什么？
Why?
我喜欢这个新的你
I like this new you.
我们必须摧毁这艘船
We have to destroy this ship.
你能带我去桥吗？
Can you get me to the bridge?
当然跟着我
Certainly. Follow me.
扎尔格
Zurg.
惊喜行动派对 我们开始了
Operation Surprise Party, here we go.
扎普 扎普！
Zap, zap!
我们需要保护我们的逃生船
We need to protect our escape ship.
所以 不要让任何机器人从那扇门进来
So, don't let any robots come through that door.
别担心 我们会把它封起来的
Don't worry, we'll seal it off.
你去找巴兹
You go find Buzz.
我会在他的狗标签上找到芯片
I'll track the chip in his dog tags.
喵喵
Meow meow.
发生了什么？
What's wrong?
我收到两个嗡嗡声信号 这不可能是对的
I'm getting two Buzz signals. That's can't be right.
我将三角测量 这会让我们离得足够近 来吧
I'll triangulate. That will get us close enough. Come on.
返回的快捷方式
A shortcut back.
这很漂亮
This is pretty neat.
我们必须走了
We have to go.
是的 好吧
Yep, all right.
哦 太好了
Oh, great.
这些控件我都不知道
I don't know any of these controls.
等待一、 V.A.N ？
Wait. I.V.A.N.?
什么事 队长？
Yes, Captain?
男孩 很高兴见到你
Boy, am I glad to see you.
两分钟后启动自毁程序
Initiate self-destruct sequence in two minutes.
你明白了 自毁倒计时开始
You got it. Self-destruct countdown initiated.
Buzz 你不想要这些很酷的技术吗？
Buzz, you don't want any of this cool technology?
只有你 伙计 来吧
Only you, buddy, come on.
-叛徒-不
-Traitor! -No.
足够地
Enough!
告诉我水晶在哪里
Just tell me where the crystal is.
好的 我们必须保护我们的逃生船
Okay, we've gotta protect our escape ship.
那么 我们怎么关上这扇门呢？
So, how do we close this door?
我不知道
I don't know.
什么你说：“别担心 我们会把它封起来的 ”
What? You said, "don't worry we'll seal it off."
好的 所以别担心 我们将
Right, so don't worry. We will.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
看 看到了吗？
Look, see?
什么
What?
喵喵
Meow meow.
现在信号更紧了
The signal is tighter now.
他必须直截了当地走这条路
He has to be straight this way.
这是很大的空间
That's a lot of space.
把它放在一起 把它放在一起
Keep it together. Keep it together.
不
No!
我不明白 信号显示Buzz在50米外
I don't understand. The signal says Buzz is 50 meters away.
他在那边
He's over there.
你认为我们不一样吗 巴兹？
You think we're not the same, Buzz?
你已经是我了 你只是还不知道而已
You're already me, you just don't know it yet.
我永远不会成为你！
I'm never gonna be you!
如果你不是我 你就不是任何人
If you're not gonna be me you're not gonna be anyone.
人工重力分离
Artificial gravity disengaged.
爆炸
Blast.
不 不
No, no.
-嘿 你在干什么-制造炸弹
-Hey, what are you doing? -Building a bomb.
很好 你需要钢笔吗？
Nice, do you need a pen?
不 在这里
No. Here.
哦 谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
薄荷糖
Peppermint.
把包装纸给我
Give me the wrapper.
那么 你可以用这些东西造一个炸弹？
So, you can just build a bomb out of that stuff?
我用更少的钱工作 现在把口香糖给我
I worked with less. Now give me the gum.
等等 我还没吃完 还有很多味道
Wait, I'm not done, there's still a lot of flavor left.
来吧
Come on!
那里当他们踩上去时 它就会爆炸
There. When they step on it it will blow up.
如果他们不踩它怎么办？
What if they don't step on it?
我的意思是 我不会踩到它 你会吗？
I mean, I wouldn't step on that, would you?
然后我们需要在上面放些重东西
Then we need to drop something heavy on it.
-只是想-不
-Just gonna... -No!
嗡嗡声
Buzz?
Buzz!
Alisha？
Alisha?
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
不 我一个人做不了 我需要帮助
No. I can't do it alone. I need help.
我不是我奶奶
I'm not my grandma.
伊兹 我不需要你奶奶 我需要你
Izzy, I don't need your grandma, I need you.
Sox 我们怎么过去？
Sox, how do we get over there?
通过气闸
Through the airlock.
穿过那里？
Through there?
外面什么都没有
There's nothing out there.
确切地没有任何阻碍
Exactly. Nothing in your way.
你直接穿过
You just go straight across.
不
No!
让我澄清一下 当它落在你的炸弹上时
Let me get this straight, when this falls on your bomb
-它肯定会爆炸-对
-it will definitely explode. -Yes.
-那会封住门吗-对
-And that will seal the door? -Yes.
但我们最好快点
But we better hurry.
我在赶时间
I am hurrying.
你为什么不快点？
Why don't you hurry?
来吧
Come on.
可以
Okay.
来吧 伊兹
Come on, Izzy.
你有这个
You got this.
哦 伙计
Oh, man.
哦 不
Oh, no.
不要往下看 也不要往上看 都是空间
Just don't look down, or up. It's all space.
到处都是 在你周围
It's everywhere. All around you.
对不起 我可能帮不了你
I'm sorry, I'm probably not helping.
直走就行了
Just go straight.
一旦你按这个方向走 你就会走
Once you push off that the direction you'll go.
但是如果我错过了呢？
But what if I miss?
不要错过
Don't miss.
什么哦 不
What? Oh, no.
不 不！
No, no!
哇！
Whoa!
Sox！
Sox!
谢谢你 伊兹
Thank you, Izzy.
没有办法进去
There is no way in.
也许我能帮上忙
Perhaps I could help.
你不能为我隐瞒 巴兹
You can't hide for me, Buzz.
这就像是躲着自己
It's like hiding from yourself.
我会一直找到你
I'll always find you.
手动超控激活
Manual override activated.
-巴斯-现在
-Buzz! -Now!
快点 我们离开这里！
Come on, let's get outta here!
我们必须炸毁这艘船
We have to blow up the ship.
没有时间了 我们永远也做不到
There's no time. We'll never make it.
哦 是的 我们会的
Oh, yes, we will.
自毁序列在十分钟内完成
Self-destruct sequence complete in ten...
-...九 八-一、 V.A.N ？一、 V.A.N ！
-...nine, eight... -I.V.A.N.? I.V.A.N.!
扎尔格
Zurg.
达比 我们必须投降
Darby, we have to surrender.
不我不会放弃
No! I am not giving up.
是的 我也不是 等等
Yep, neither am I. Hold on.
-...五 四-走吧
-...five, four... -Let's go.
-...三 二-所有人 上车
-...three, two... -Everyone, get in.
...一
...one.
巴斯光年任务日志
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
我们摧毁了Zurg的飞船和Zurg本人
We've destroyed the Zurg's ship and Zurg himself.
现在我只要追上犰狳就能--
Now I just have to catch up to the Armadillo in order to--
去什么地方？
Going somewhere?
警告 发动机损坏是灾难性的
Warning, engine damage is catastrophic.
巴斯光年任务日志 我现在拥有水晶
Buzz Lightyear mission log. I now have the crystal in my possession,
终于可以完成任务了
and can finally, at long last finish the mission.
我要回去再谈一次 巴兹
I'm gonna go back and matter again, Buzz.
你呢？
And you?
你会像从来没有在这里一样
You will be like you have never here.
准备去死
Prepare to die.
今天不行 祖格
Not today, Zurg.
我们已经进入了行星的引力
We've entered the planet's gravitational pull.
我们会坠机吗?
Are we gonna crash?
恐怕是这样的
I'm afraid so.
嗡嗡声!
Buzz!
我做不到
I can't do it.
Buzz,没关系
Buzz, it's okay.
我们可以
We can.
你能保持船平稳吗?
Can you keep the ship steady?
是的 我想是的
Yeah. I think so.
好了 萨克斯 把应急电池熔在一起那是飞行控制的动力
Okay, Sox, fuse the emergency battery the power of flight controls.
明白了
Got it.
我需要一个副驾驶
I'll need a co-pilot.
但我只在模拟器中做过
Okay, but I've only done this in the simulator.
好吧 马上就要成真了
Well, it's about to get real.
记住 拉上轭架
Remember, pull back on the yoke--
很容易 是的 对不起 从现在开始慢慢来
-Easy. -Yep. Sorry. Nice and easy from now on.
这不是工作!
It's not working!
我们进得太快了
We're going in too fast.
-I.V.A.N -是的,船长?
-I.V.A.N. -Yes, Captain?
-我们开得太快了 祝贺你!
-We're going too fast. -Congratulations!
我们不需要五彩纸屑 我们需要刹车!
We don't need confetti, we need brakes!
哦,我知道!
Oh, I know!
——空气制动!在地板上
-The air brake! -On the floor.
Darby !
Darby!
-卡住了 -什么?
-It's stuck. -What?
盖子卡住了
The cover, it's stuck.
我需要一把螺丝刀 或者一把理发钳
I need a screwdriver, or a hair clipper
某种小楔子
Some sort of a small wedge.
我拿到笔了!
I've got the pen!
嗡嗡声!-大家都没事吧?
-Buzz! - Is everyone okay?
-是的 我是这样认为的
-Yeah. -I think so.
警察!每一个人,快跑!
The cops! Everybody, run!
等等 只是救援队而已
Wait. It's just the rescue team.
对 好吧
Right. Okay.
你看起来是个好公民 是什么导致你入狱的?
You seem like a decent citizen. What led to your incarceration?
我偷了一艘船
I stole a ship.
我们当中谁没有偷过一艘船…
Who among us hasn't stolen a ship in a moment of...
相对绝望?
relative desperation?
我是个有资源的人 我的武器是独创性
I'm a man of resources. My weapon is ingenuity.
我什么都能做!
I can do anything!
你能别对着我耳朵嚷嚷吗?
Can you not shout in my ear?
是的,抱歉
Yep, sorry.
你明白吗?
You're okay?
su.b .T
我在太空
I was in space.
你奶奶会为你感到骄傲的
Your grandma would be proud.
她也会为你骄傲的
She'd be proud of you too.
她总是
She always was.
等等 你的水晶呢?
Wait. Where is your crystal?
这是一去不复返了
It's gone.
但是你的使命……
But your mission...
你想回家
You wanted to go home.
这么长时间以来 我第一次
You know, for the first time in a long time
我感觉就像在家里一样
I feel like I am home.
Zurg
Zurg.
当心!
Look out!
哇?
Whoa?
现在停止!
Stop right now!
光年
Lightyear.
你带着星际司令部的财产潜逃 偷了实验飞船
You absconded with Star Command property, stolen experimental spacecraft
违抗指挥官的直接命令
and defied a direct order from your commander.
我要把你扔进寨子里
I gotta throw you into stockade.
但我对你另有安排
But I have other plans for you.
我们想让你建立一个新版本的太空游骑兵队
We want you to start a new version of the Space Ranger Corps.
宇宙保护部门
Universe Protection Division.
你会再次成为太空骑警的 巴斯
You're gonna be a Space Ranger again, Buzz.
您可以手动选择您的团队从Zap巡逻的最好的
You can hand-select your team from the very best of the Zap Patrol
按照你的喜好训练它们
and train them to your liking.
攻击,攻击!
Zap, zap!
你真是太好了 先生
Well, that's very kind of you, sir.
但恐怕我不得不拒绝
But I'm afraid I'm going to have to decline.
我已经有我的团队了
I already have my team.
这些新西装太棒了 爆破手 火箭翼
These new suits are amazing. Arm blaster, rocket wings.
不过它可能需要一支笔
It could use a pen though.
真不敢相信我被允许带着这个 我希望我有两个
I can't believe I'm allowed to carry this. I wish I had two of them.
你没有案底 你自由了 还有武器
You got a clean record. and you're free and armed.
你还在抱怨什么?
How are you still complaining?
我因为行为好而被免职 不是因为态度好
I got off for good behavior, not good attitude.
我从来不穿裤子
You know, I never wear pants,
但突然觉得不穿裤子很奇怪
but suddenly it feels weird to not be wearing pants.
不穿裤子会不会很奇怪?
Does it look weird without pants?
不 你看起来不错
No, you look good.
我希望我能做到
I wish I could pull that off.
看 奶奶 我是太空骑警
Look, Grandma, I'm a Space Ranger.
就像你
Just like you.
好了 队员们 我们在第四区的伽玛象限接收到一个信号
All right, team, we've picked up a signal in the Gamma Quadrant of Sector 4.
我们不知道它是什么 但我们不能等着它入侵我们的家园
We don't know what it is, but we're not gonna wait for it to invade our home.
复制,指挥官 你可以信赖我们
Copy, Commander. You can count on us.
巴斯光年任务日志 明星日期4071
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date 4071.
作为宇宙精英保护小组的成员
As members of the Elite Universe Protection Unit
太空游骑兵队的
of the Space Ranger Corps,
我们的任务是保护银河系免受入侵的威胁
we've been charged to protect the galaxy from the threat of invasion
远离银河联盟的死敌
from any sworn enemies of The Galaxy Alliance.
好了 各位 确保系好了
Okay, everyone, make sure you're securely fastened.
-我们什么都有了?弹药吗?—
-Do we have everything? Munitions? -Check.
食物吗?我把三明治
-Sustenance? -I brought sandwiches.
你的肚子会没事吗?
And your tummy will be okay?
——集 -好的
-All set. -All right.
我忘了什么吗?
Am I forgetting anything?
我想我们准备好了
I think we're ready.
你好 我是你的内部声控导航
Hello, I am your internal voice-activated navigator.
很高兴你回来 静脉注射
Good to have you back, I.V.A.N.
光年船长 准备发射
Captain Lightyear, ready for launch.
袜吗?猫叫?
-Sox? -Meow?
启动hyper-launch I.V.A.N
I.V.A.N., initiate hyper-launch.
当然可以
Certainly.
好了 太空游骑兵 我们开始吧
All right, Space Rangers. Here we go.
到正无穷
To infinity
甚至更远
and beyond.
请继续关注01:35:50和01:43:37的两个片尾场景 欢呼 sub.T
Keep tuned for TWO post credit scenes at 01:35:50 and 01:43:37. Cheers. sub.T
文字记录:sub.Trader subscene.com
Transcript by sub.Trader subscene.com
激光的盾牌
Laser shield.
现在 你是否更喜欢风景优美的路线
Now, should you prefer a more scenic route
你要往南走 经过溴化物沼泽
you'll want to head south past the bromite swamps,
令人惊叹的景象 至少他们是这么告诉我的
a breathtaking sight, or so I am told.
但如果你赶时间 这是最直接的路线
But if you are in a hurry, this would be your most direct route.
有问题吗?
Any questions?
喂?
Hello?